ELISA ESCAPA OTANI

8722 36th Ave. College Park MD 20740 (301) 357-5411 <u>escapa.elisa@gmail.com</u> http://terpconnect.umd.edu/~eescapa

PROFILE

Award-winning web developer specialized in mobile development and UI/UX web design with experience in Android SDK (Java), Eclipse, GitHub, Visual Studio 2010, ASP.NET and C#. Highly engaged community member with leadership and management skills. Recognized as an approachable and reliable team player.

EDUCATION

May 2014: Bachelor of Arts, Communication, *University of Maryland College Park* June 2010: High School, *Benjamin Franklin International School*, Barcelona Spain

RELATED EXPERIENCE

Web/Mobile Developer, UMD Adele H. Stamp Student Union

August 2011 - Present

- Developed web applications using Visual Studio 2010, ASP.NET, C#, SQL, Android SDK on Java, and JSON
- Currently developing an Android app that displays information on the Stamp and receives user feedback
- Designed and implemented multi-feature web forms and administration pages, improving productivity and efficiency for mass registration for student organization funding, volunteer opportunities, and other services
- Received the Stamp Employee Standout Award (May 2012)

Freelance Web Developer, Katz Global Strategies

November 2013 - January 2014

- Implemented a Homeland Security information website through HostGator and WordPress
- HTML, CSS, PHP, Adobe Illustrator & Photoshop CS6 for graphics

UI/UX Design & Development Intern, Unitrends

May 2013 - August 2013

- Designed and developed UX improvements for the next major release of the virtualization backup product, including a digital product tour for new user onboarding
- Python, Django, jQuery, HTML5, and CSS; PyCharm and PostgreSQL; on Linux Ubuntu through VMware vSphere

Mobile Web Developer, Code for Community Challenge

January 2013 - April 2013

- Developed the first-place winning mobile web app for the Prince George's County Department of Parks and Recreation that displays information on community centers in the county using geo-location
- HTML, CSS, jQuery, Responsive Web Design, Eclipse, and Google Code Repositories

ACTIVITIES

President, Shout "Fire!" Film Society of UMD	September 2013 – Present
Taste of Japan 2014 Event Coordinator, Japanese-American Student Association: Managed 6 staff and 30 volunteers for an annual event attended by 300 people	September 2013 – Present
Short Film Director ("Voicemail")	October 2012
English Tutor, UMD Tutorial Program for foreign student athletes	January 2012 – May 2012
Short Film Director Finalist, Campus MovieFest ("Maladroid")	March 2012
Secretary, Shout "Fire!" Film Society	September 2011 – May 2013

PERSONAL

- Directs and edits short films as a hobby using Final Cut Express, iMovie
- Creates Web Graphics with Adobe Photoshop & Illustrator CS6, Gimp
- Fluent in English and Spanish. Conversational in Japanese and French
- Enjoys traveling, table tennis, badminton, and skiing